人类正处于一个转折点
Humanity is at a turning point,
我们在生存的竞争中
and we are now in the race of our lives.
一个为了环境的赛事
A race for the environment
一个平等的赛事
A race for equality
一个电动化的赛事
A race powered by electric
Extreme E这场全球征程，将提供世界上首项纯电动性别平等的赛车运动
Extreme E is a global voyage that will provide a world first all-electric gender equal motorsport
强调气候变暖的冲击，推广电动化
to highlight the impacts of climate change and promote electrification
车手们已经来到沙特阿拉伯驰骋
The drivers have already taken to the wheel in the deserts of Saudi Arabia
现在要看看究竟谁能摘取桂冠
and it's now time to see who will take the crown in the kingdom
Extreme E的揭幕战在萨特阿拉伯沙漠的深处举办
The inaugural round of Extreme E is being held deep in the deserts of Saudi Arabia
此地风景美丽而残酷
an unforgiving but beautiful landscape
麦地那北部的绿洲和河谷
The natural oasis and wadis around the northern region of Medina
数千年来吸引着众多人类文明在此安居
have attracted civilizations for thousands of years
古国在这片沙地留下印记
with ancient kingdoms leaving their mark in the sands
到12世纪，这个地区的人民用泥砖建造了一个城镇
By the 12th century the people of the region had built a town of mud brick houses within a walled settlement
至今都是AlUla人民的安居之所
that until very recently was the home of the people of AlUla
我们所在的地方被称为AlUla之城
We are in a place called the old town of AlUla
这座城有750年的历史了
This city is 750 years old
我们有大约900座房屋
And we have around 900 houses
因为AlUla处于国际香料交易的必经之路上
Because AlUla is lying in the middle of the international trading route of incense and spices
所以AlUla当时就像一个大市场
so AlUla it was like a big market in that time because of the location
所以当时AlUla是十分重要的
so AlUla it was very important
80年代中期以前，人们一直住在这里
People used to lived here up to the middle of the 80s
直到大约1982年，人们才搬进了通水通电的木屋
so people moved around 1982 to wooden houses
which include water and electricity
现在AlUla古城由阿拉伯埃尔奥拉皇家委员会修复
The old town of AlUla is being restored now by royal commission
就像一个开放的博物馆
It's like an open museum
所到之处，你都能看到古迹
Everywhere you go you can see old ancient sites
这就是AlUla
So this is the AlUla
美丽的历史，美丽的人民
Beautiful history and beautiful people
人民也使Alula更美丽
And the people make AlUla more beautiful
第一天的X-Prix沙漠分站赛在alula附近的广袤沙漠中举行
Day one of the Desert X-Prix in the stunning deserts near AlUla
排位赛精彩连连，其结果将决定谁晋级第二天的半决赛
saw an action-packed qualifying to decide who would do battle in the semi-finals the very next day
Veloce Racing的车手Stéphane Sarrazin在他的出场圈
As Veloce Racing driver Stéphane Sarrazin was on his and the team's opening lap
他在赛道的下坡段末端撞到了一颗树根
He hit an unsighted tree root at the bottom of the massive drop section of the track
严重的事故损伤了他们的Odyssey 21的防滚架
The huge crash damaged the roll cage of their Odyssey 21,
意味着
meaning unfortunately for them,
他们将不能参加第二天的比赛
they wouldn't be able to race on day two
Segi TV Chip Ganassi Racing队因为技术故障导致不能在排位赛做出成绩
Segi TV Chip Ganassi Racing were unable to set a qualifying time due to a technical issue
意味着他们不能向对手展示他们的真实实力
meaning they couldn't show their fellow competitors what they were made of
ABT Cupra队的前半圈看起来很有竞争力
Despite looking strong during the first half of the lap
但车手Claudia Hürtgen的一个小失误导致了排位赛中的翻车
The smallest of mistakes for ABT Cupra driver Claudia Hürtgen was all it took to send their car rolling during qualifying
没事，我没事
Okay, I'm okay.
对不起
Sorry guys
全队争分夺秒修车，为第二天做准备
A true team race was on to rebuild the car in time for day two
就连车手Mattias Ekström也开始工作，直到深夜
Even driver Mattias Ekström got stuck in as their efforts continued into the night
第二天的X-Prix沙漠分站赛进行Shootout
The second day of the Desert X-Prix saw racing action in the form of the Shootout
来决定没进半决赛的队伍的名次
to decide the final finishing places for the teams that missed out on the semi-final
Veloce队因为前一天的事故，判为第九名
With Veloce out of the running due to their crash a day earlier finishing ninth overall
这将是第七名和第八名之间一对一的较量
It was to be a head-to-head battle to decide seventh and eighth
Chip Ganassi 对 ABT Cupra
Chip Ganassi versus ABT Cupra
Sara Price 对 Mattias Ekström
Sara Price versus Mattias Ekström
已经做好发车准备
We are ready to go in the desert
接下来将是两圈的比赛
Two laps await them
比赛开始
And we are off
两辆车后轮掀起大量沙尘
Both cars digging the backs
努力在沙地上找到一些抓地力
Gripping hole the sand
沙尘飞扬
The dust flying
他们两人的起步速度看起来差不多
It looks like a fairly equal start to both of them
领先的是
Taking the lead
是Chip Ganassi的车
it is a Chip Ganassi car
Sara Price起步后获得领先
Sara Price a fantastic lead off the start there
她已经拉开了巨大的优势
She's already taken a huge advantage into this
她开过了两边的凸起
She goes past the big boulders either side
她将穿过第一个检查点
She's making it down to the first gate
哦她好像遇到了一些问题
Oh look she must have some sort of issue
因为Ekström看起来又夺回了领先的位置
because it looks like uh that it's it's Ekström making the managing to take the lead
他们正驶向第一个检查点
and as they go down to the first gate
Ekström不知道从哪里冒出来的，成功夺回了领先位置
it does look indeed like Ekström has managed to claw that back somehow out of nowhere
在起步后被Price使用power boost超过之后
After initially being beaten off the line by Price using her one hyperdrive power boost early in the race
Ekström抓住时机使用他的power boost在下坡之前夺回领先
Ekström timed his boost well to take back the lead before the drop
差距正在拉开
The gap is opening up isn't it
别忘了，Sara还没有开过完整的一圈
Sara, we've said, hasn't had a lap, don't forget
昨天在试航中开了半圈
Half of a lap in Shakedown, yesterday
她一整圈都没有转向助力
she fought the car with no power steering around the entire circuit
在换人区
At the switch zone
Claudia Hürtgen在前一天事故之后第一次再跳上车
Claudia Hürtgen jumped into the ABT Cupra car for the first time since a huge crash the previous day
Kyle LeDuc接过方向盘开始追赶
Kyle LeDuc took to the Chip Ganassi wheel looking to chase down the lead
现在是一场精彩的追逐战
This is a fascinating chase down battle now
LeDuc做的也很不错
LeDuc is doing a good job as well
现在差距缩小到16秒
Now the gaps come down for 16 seconds
赛道上一段追进了8秒
so eight seconds on that last section of the track
Hürtgen过沙丘的时候有点紧张
Hürtgen has been a bit tense over the top of the dune
完全横行
Absolutely sideways
Kyle LeDuc正在全力追近
Kyle LeDuc is on it now
他就在后面
He's right up behind
沙尘不太严重
The dust isn't too bad
但也绝对有影响
It is proper sand
这里是Hürtgen昨天出事故的地方
That's where Hürtgen and had her crash yesterday
她减速了
She's got it backed off
他在尘土中寻找超车线路
He's in the dust now looking for a way through
没松油门！
No lifting!
哦他撞上她了！
Oh he hits her!
在看不见的情况下直接追尾Hürtgen
Oh into the back he hits Hürtgen completely unsighted
他追尾了
He hit the back of the car
这不是我们希望看到的
That's not what we wanted to see
她
停车了
我
的
天
呐
她
停在
我
我前
我前面
我前面了
我们
都
停了
我
没事
她
她停
她停住
她停住了
兄弟
全是
土
啊啊啊啊啊啊啊啊啊
什么
情况？
你没
事吧
什么
情况
你
撞
到
我
了
哦
感觉像你
停下了
没有
我撞你的时候
速度很快
实在抱歉
我没事，但我简直不敢相信这次事故
I'm here and I cannot believe what happened
我再一次从山坡上冲下来
Yeah so I was coming down the hill again
同一个山坡
The same hill
路上有个很大的突起
There were a big bump
我松油门为了保证安全
and I released the throttle to be safe
这时候我从后面收到了巨大的冲击
And at this moment I had a huge impact from the rear
然后车停了
And then again the car will stop,
到后面一看，完全撞毁了
and come in the rear completely destroyed
这两队的第一场艰难的Extreme E比赛就这样戏剧性的结束了
A dramatic ending to a tough first Extreme E event for both teams
ABT Cupra排在第七名
with ABT Cupra finishing seventh
Segi TV Chip Ganassi Racing排在第八
and Segi TV Chip Ganassi Racing taking eighth overall
尽管这个国家没有永久性的河流
Although a country with no permanent rivers
但阿拉伯沙漠中有许多绿洲，为当地社区提供重要的资源
Saudi Arabia's deserts have numerous oases that provide vital resources to the local communities
在阿拉伯被称为干谷
Known in Arabic as a wadi,
这些环境为畜牧业和农业提供了肥沃的土壤
these environments create fertile soils for livestock and agriculture
来到这里感觉就像
Arriving here is like
哇，我到了这么一个美丽充满生机的地方
wow, I've arrived in this beautiful green place
这和外面的景观大相径庭
It's the contrast of the landscape of as you enter the oasis
千年以来，朝圣者和旅人在这里相遇
Pilgrims and travelers and people over thousands of years have happened upon this place
人类文明能在此地建立的原因是，这里有干谷，有地下水资源
The reason for those civilizations being here was because of the the wadi and the water that was contained underground
在沙漠地下有大量的水源
Under the desert there's large supplies of water
用水量应该取决于蓄水层的增水量
How much water you take out it should be ruled by how much water is coming into the aquifer
所以如果你将更多的水用在庄家和社区中
and so if you take out more water for planting more crops or using more for your community
如果井水水位下降，无法得到补充，就像AlUla这里的情况一样
If the well levels are going down it's not being replenished which is the case here in AlUla
我们就要考虑如何减少我们的用水量
we need to look at how do we reduce the amount of water that we're using
这样水位就能回升
so that the level of the wells can come back up again
所以我们必须考虑如何更高效地使用水资源
And so we really have to look at how do we use water more efficiently
AlUla就是个很好的例子
And AlUla is a perfect example of that
我们可以证明，在这种传统绿洲中
In that we can demonstrate that here in an oasis in a traditional oasis,
我们可以通过提高用水效率来重新实现可持续发展
we can recapture that sustainability and through water use efficiency
传统的漫灌或地表灌溉需要大量的水
Traditionally flood irrigation or surface irrigation uses a very large amount of water,
相比之下如果我们转而采用滴灌和微灌系统
whereas if we move over to drip systems and micro irrigation systems,
我们能减少最多50%的用水量
we're able to reduce the water to as much as 50 percent,
而仍然获得相同甚至更好的收益
and still get the same harvest or even more harvest
所以如果我们把传统方法和现代科技结合起来
And so it is about combining the best of traditional techniques with modern technology at the same time
管理好绿洲，这样我们就可以用更少的代价获得更多效益，可以这么说
and so managing the oasis so that we're able to get more for less so to speak
这就是我们发展的方向
That's the, that's the way forward for us
水在Odyssey 21的充电过程中也扮演着重要的角色
Water plays a key role in the charging of Extreme E fleet of Odyssey 21 cars,
它们由独立氢燃料电池供能
as they are powered by a fully off-grid hydrogen fuel cell
氢能一般由太阳能转化来
So hydrogen is traditionally produced via solar
所以氢能被称为绿色能源
It's known as green hydrogen
基本是就是一个水电解的过程
It's basically a process of electrolysis which takes water
你向水中传递能量
And you basically inject a bit of power
然后就可以把H₂O分解为氢气和氧气
and you split the water H₂O into hydrogen and oxygen
其中的氢气被用于我们的燃料电池
And so the hydrogen goes into our fuel cell
这是它环保的原因
and that's really what makes it green
我们很自豪能有这样一套系统
Very proud moment of having the system here
同时也很高兴能鉴证这个伟大的赛事并做出贡献
But also great to be contributing to such a great race, such a great initiative and vision
能够为所有赛车提供零排放的氢燃料电池充电真是太棒了
Providing the charging for all race vehicles with hydrogen fuel cells with zero emissions is just fantastic
沙特阿拉伯有潜力成为世界上真正大量使用氢能源的国家之一
Saudi Arabia has the potential to be one of the the real superpowers in hydrogen generation around the world
我们能看到其中的收益
We've certainly seen a lot of interest,
氢能源正在成为沙特能源中很重要的一部分
and on how the hydrogen is going to become part of the energy mix in in Saudi,
像我们这样的技术
and how technologies like ours
能够大规模取代柴油和化石燃料发电
will start to see a massive displacement of diesel and traditional fossil fuel based power generation
所以说，参与到沙特创造生态系统的故事中非常棒
So you know be part of that story that Saudi is creating the ecosystem is fantastic
这是我们很荣幸能参与的事情
and one that we're very proud to be part of
我们已经和当地的沙特公司签订了一项协议
We've already signed one agreement with a local Saudi company
他们是世界上最大的柴油发动机提供商之一
They're one of the largest distributors of diesel engines in the world
我们已经开始看到Extreme E带来的积极影响了
So we're already starting to see the benefits of what extreme E is proposing
尤其是在推动工业中对气候变化的认识上
in terms of you know driving climate change awareness amongst industry
这才是我们要传递的重要信息
And it's really that's the key message
我们已经从Extreme E中看到了实实在在的益处
and we've now got tangible benefits that we're starting to see from Extreme E
在AlUla旁这片广袤而美丽的沙漠中
In the vast and beautiful deserts near AlUla
舞台布置好了
The stage was set
车辆充好电了
The cars were fully charged
车手和车队已经准备好推动赛车界电动化
And the drivers and teams were ready to electrify the motorsport world,
他们将第一次并肩前行
as they went three abreast for the first time
第一天排位赛前三名的选手晋级半决赛
The top three qualifiers from day one went through to the semi-final race
从中决定决赛中的两个位置
where two positions in the final were up for grabs
RXR、ACCIONA Sainz和X-44依次列开
RXR lined up alongside ACCIONA Sainz and X-44
在并列起步之后
After a super tight wheel-to-wheel start,
RXR的Johan Kristoffersson一个完美的切线之后获得领先，把Sainz和X-44甩在尘土中
RXR's Johan Kristoffersson executed a perfect cutback to take the lead and leave Sainz and X-44 in the dust,
队友Molly Taylor接过车后完美带回
setting up his teammate Molly Taylor to take over and bring the car home
X-44第二个冲过终点线，将在决赛中加入
X-44 would join them in the final after crossing the line in second place
接下来的Crazy Race将决定谁获得剩下的一个位置
The Crazy Race was next to decide who would claim the last remaining spot
Andretti United队的Hansen比他的对手在起步上抓地力更好
Andretti United's Timmy Hansen managed to get more grip and a better jump off the start than his rivals
他在一圈中持续扩大领先优势
He extended the lead throughout the lap
交给Catie Munnings后，她专注地跑出了完美的一圈
handing over to Catie Munnings who stayed laser focused completing her lap perfectly
让他们继续争夺X-Prix沙漠分站赛冠军
and kept them in the fight for the Desert X-Prix crown
决赛前
Before the final could start,
发车位置需要确定
the grid needed to be set
Grid Play允许观众们为他们喜欢的车手投票
Grid Play sees fans vote for their favorite drivers
让他们在决赛中优先选择出发位置
to give them first pick of starting position in the final
但是还有转折的机会
But there's a twist
其他队伍可以把自己的票贡献给进入决赛名单的队伍
The other teams can give their votes to one of the finalists
从而影响比赛
influencing the race
我们想让观众来帮帮我们
Guys we want the audience to help us
支持X-44的？
Anyone scream for X-44
中间中间
Middle, middle
支持RXR的？
At RXR
第一个
Number one
支持Andretti的？
that's Andretti
这些都是大腕
These are really big names
他们都是大佬
and they're all badasses
但是他们黑马
but they're the underdogs and
我们能体会到，所以...
we can relate so
很难选择啊
It's very difficult to pick with these teams
我在F1里和这两位赛了好几年了
These two I've raced with for many many years in F1
他们时不时还把我虐的挺惨
And they've kicked my asses at times
所以我们要投给...
So we're gonna go
不是针对谁
Nothing personal
但是Zak是我的好朋友
But Zak is a good friend
他答应在迈凯伦给我打个折
He promised me a good discount in the McLaren
所有额外投票全部投给Andretti United，意味着他们可以第一个选
All the extra votes for Andretti United meant they got first pick
他们选择了一号位
And they went for position one
在Crazy Race他们在这个发车位起步不错
where they'd had huge success off the start in the Crazy Race
RXR选择中间的位置
RXR chose the middle slot
X-44最终在三号位起步
with X-44 ending up in the third position
起步位置确定后
And with the starting lineup complete,
现在将决出谁拿到冠军
it was time to crown a champion
这是决赛的发车顺位
This is your lineup for the final
Timmy Hansen和Catie Munnings所在的Andretti United队在中间
Timmy Hansen and Catie Munnings for Andretti United in the middle
Johan Kristoffersson和Molly Taylor所在的RXR队
Johan Kristoffersson and Molly Taylor for RXR, Rosberg Extreme Racing
在右手侧的是X-44队的Sebastian Loeb和Christina Gutierrez
On the right-hand side Sebastian Loeb and Christina Gutierrez for X-44
队员们在控制中心
Teams are in the command center
气氛紧张起来
nerves are rising
他们目不转睛地盯着灯
Get their eyes completely focused on the lights
等着两侧的灯变为绿色
Look either side of the grid for the green
注意谁能起步起的最好
and then watch to see who gets the best getaway
开始了
Here we go
外侧绿灯亮起
Green light on the outside
X-44轮胎空转很明显
Lots and lots of wheels pin for X-44
Timmy Hansen再次在内侧起步很好
Timmy Hansen with an amazing start on the inside again
他直接把其他人抛开
He's absolutely blown them away
他是不是在起步使用了power boost呢？
Has he though used hyperdrive off the line
Kristoffersson变到外线
Kristoffersson moving out wide
想让X-44进到沙尘里
trying to move the X-44 car into the dust
而他也跑大了
and he runs out wide as well
那么X-44从外侧走交叉线
so X-44 moving across the outside line
Loeb尝试切回来
Sebastian Loeb though gonna try and make the cut back across
Johan在半决赛中用这一招成功过
Johan Kristoffersson made that work in his semi-final
Hansen在前面领先很远
Timmy Hansen though miles out in front of them
到了第一弯
There is turn one
他们正在追近
They're gaining on him now
我想知道他们是不是等着晚一点再用power boost
I wonder if they've waited to use their hyperdrive just a little bit later
Johan走大了
Kristoffersson goes out wide
现在他要切回来
Now he's gonna make the cut back and
在弯中带一些速度
try and carry the speed through the corner
Hansen领先，Johan紧随其后
Hansen lead to Kristoffersson right behind him
进入比较颠簸的部分
Into the bumpy section now
这是Johan车上的镜头
On board with Kristoffersson
让我们看看是谁在前
Let's take a look and see who is in front
是Johan
It's Johan
Johan成功获得领先，车尾甩的很高
Johan has managed to get in front again as he kicks the car really high
他又一次在一号弯使用这个超车动作
He managed to get that move done again karoon in turn one
我觉得Lobe好像遇到了问题
I think Lobe's got some sort of an issue there
他在二号弯之前很挣扎
He was really struggling at up in turn two
我们再看一下
We'll see as the lap unfold
没有
转向
助力
没有
转向
助力
Johan在前面拉开了
Up at the front though Kristoffersson has pulled
他拉开了很大的距离优势
He's pulled a massacre
看看，他已经过了跳坡
Look he's got that whole jump ahead
RXR队的Johan速度很快
Such high speeds now for Kristoffersson in the Rosberg team
现在是135Kph
He's up to 135 kilometers an hour
Rosberg要高兴成狗了😂
Nico Rosberg could be jumping up and down like a cocker spaniel with an excitement
Molly Taylor跑到车的另一侧
Molly Taylor running around the other side of the car
Johan干的很漂亮，他已经出来了
Kristoffersson's done a great job he's out
这周末的任务完成了
Job done for the weekend
出来的时候会感觉很轻松
There's a sense of relief when you get out
因为你知道你作为车手已经完成自己的任务了
because you know you've done your bit as a driver
然后你交付给队友
And you hand over to your teammates
Molly现在要肩负重任把车带回
The pressure was now on Molly Taylor to bring the car home
她的目标很明确
But her focus was clear
在冲向胜利光辉的路上，她不能犯任何错误
She wasn't going to make a mistake in her charge for the glory
比赛结果很明显
This is gonna be the one
第一个获得Extreme E分站赛冠军的将是Molly Taylor
This is gonna be Molly Taylor winning the first ever Extreme E X-Prix
她冲线了
She crosses the line
干的很漂亮
She has done a fabulous job
怪不得她在笑
and no wonder she is smiling
因为她和Johan一起为他们的F1冠军老板Rosberg带回了一个第一名
because her and Kristoffersson have bought that car home for their boss for the manager for Nico Rosberg, the Formula One world champion
多么精彩的赛季开场秀啊
We had an amazing start to the season
我们来参加的时候都不知道应该报什么样的希望
We all came in here not knowing what to expect
结果我们在每一节都是最快，半决赛和决赛
and we've been the fastest in every hit and semi and final
所以就 嗯很惊喜
So it's just yeah it's been amazing
另外特别感谢Johan
And huge thanks to Johan
当然也感谢车队
You know congrats to the team as well
能把带我们来到这里
to bring us here
他们出色的工作保证了每次车辆和我与Molly的安全
And they've done an amazing job to get the car to me and Molly in one piece every time
并且Molly做的也很出色
and yeah and then also Molly have done a fantastic job
我们在周日的半决赛和决赛都不错
We had a very good semi-final and final today on Sunday
所以我们很开心
So yeah just um so so happy
十分感谢车队的这周末工作
So thankful to the whole effort that the team did this weekend
所有事情都进展顺利
I mean everything has come together so well
我们合作的很好，尤其要感谢Molly和Johan
We work together so well and especially specifically Molly and Johan
这周末在赛道上的表现真不错
What a phenomenal driving they've done all weekend
这里环境很艰难
You know and it's been such tough conditions there
不能出现任何失误，难以置信的速度，两个人都是
Not a foot wrong, unbelievable speed, both of them you know
真的太棒了
so it's just awesome
我们现在将冠军奖杯交给RXR队
We'll now present the first place trophies to Rosberg X Racing
在第一场精彩的X-Prix沙漠分站赛之后
After an incredible first X-Prix in the deserts of Saudi Arabia
沙尘落定，这个地区的生活也要继续
The dust would settle and everyday life in the region would resume
在这样一个干热的国家，新鲜的水资源是很有限的
For such a hot and dry country with very limited fresh water
想农业这样的产业面临着巨大的问题
Industries such as agriculture face a huge problem
为了解决这个问题
To help solve this,
阿卜杜拉国王科技大学的科学家
scientists at the King Abdullah University for Science and Technology
正在努力解决资源短缺的问题
are working on ways to mitigate the lack of such a vital resource
85%的水源被用于农业生产
85% of all fresh water is used in the production of agriculture
即使是在中东的这样一个大量进口粮食的国家
Now even in the middle east which imports a huge percentage of its food,
也会有大量的水资源被用于农业生产
there's a very significant amount of water that's used in agricultural production
我们开发的是一个能够反应全国各个农田状态的框架
And what we've developed is a framework that maps individual fields across the country,
利用机器学习、云计算，我们可以精确到每个农田
using machine learning, cloud computing, that can go down to the scale of an individual field
统计出用了多少水
and tell how much water is being used
而我们现在在考虑一种矩阵系统，比如卫星和无人机能提供给我们的
But now we're actually looking at some of the other metrics that systems like satellites and UAVs can provide
因为我们要做到精准施营养、水分、肥料，从而调整生产
Because we have to be able to precisely supply the nutrients, the water, the fertilizers into those plant systems to optimize the production
这才是精准农业的核心
And that's really the heart of precision agriculture
根据估算，到2050年大约会有90亿人口居住在地球
Projections looking forward in time indicate that with nine billion people potentially inhabiting the earth by 2050
我们需要增加食物产量
We're going to have to increase our food production
这就是为什么有大量的研究不仅是针对农作物生产系统的适应性
So that's why there's a lot of research being done on resiliency in crop production systems
同时也针对农作物本身
But also in agricultural crops themselves
我们可以利用无人机和地面上的传感器
where we use our technologies with UAVs and on-ground sensors
来帮助寻找那些更适应恶劣环境或恶劣条件的农作物
to help identify those types of crops that are better suited to either harsher environments or harsher conditions
教授们正在考虑缺水问题的另一种解决方法是
One solution to the lack of fresh water also being worked on at the university
在海水浇灌农作物方面做出创新
is innovative research into use of sea water on food crops
正如同你看到高科技可以让车飞驰，
Just like you've got amazing technologies being developed and used for driving cars around at high speed and doing amazing sports
我们同样也可以用高科技来减少人类活动的碳足迹
We can also use technologies to try to reduce the environmental footprint of our activities
一种方式是寻找能在盐水中生长的农作物
One way to do that is to develop crops which can grow in salty water,
最终到海水
and ultimately, seawater
我们种植的植物越能忍受高盐，海水中的高浓度钠和氯，就越好
The more we're able to grow plants that can tolerate that high level of salt the sodium and chloride that's in that seawater, the better
我们正在尝试做的是利用育种、基因组学和我们的一些高科技，从基因上改进它
And what we're trying to do is genetically improve this, using breeding and genomics and some of our high technologies
使种籽变大产量增大
to make the seeds bigger make the yields larger
这样这些植物在田里生成更加经济
So these plants can be grown economically viably in fields
这样农民可以用海水灌溉而收获谷物
so farmers can grow them irrigate them with seawater and harvest the grain
有一个现在我们可以做到的有意思的操作
One of the interesting things we're able to do
是像这种两部分嫁接组成的植物
is have the plant made up of two halves
我们现在在进行的是寻找特殊的植物根部
What we're doing is seeing if we can develop root stocks
下半部分西红柿的根是能在盐渍土壤中生长的特殊品种
The bottom half of the tomato which is specialized in being able to grow well in saline soils
可以帮助上半部分的植物结出果实
and help the top half of the plant produce its fruits
尽管土壤和水都含盐
despite the soil and the water being saline
你可以观察这里
So you can see this here
下面是非常耐盐的植物根部
where we've got a very salt tolerant bottom half of the plant
上面是可以结出可口果实的部分
and then a very tasty if you like top half of the plants
我们的农业系统面临着巨大的挑战
We've got massive challenges with the agricultural system
不够具备可持续性，需要改变
It's not sustainable. It has to change
而且我坚信可以改变
But I'm optimistic that it can change
因为我们有这么好的技术可供使用
Because we've got fabulous technologies at a disposal
这些技术可以让我们改善植物
which are going to allow us to improve the plants
改善种植方式来减少食品带来的碳足迹
and improve the way we grow the plants to reduce the environmental footprint of our food
我们都想吃
We all want to eat
我们都想吃好
We all want to eat well
我们都有权利吃好
We'll have a right to eat well
但是我们一定要减少饮食带来的影响
But we really do also need to reduce the impact of our eating
感谢对科技的智慧合理的利用，我认为我们可以做到
and I think we can do this thanks to intelligent use, deployments of technologies
随着第一轮的结束
With round one complete
比赛冠军Molly和Johan回顾了他们是如何为RXR带回第一个系列赛奖杯的
race winners Molly Taylor and Johann Kristoffersson took the time to break down how they took their first trophy of the series for Rosberg X Racing
现在不行
Not this time
我觉得是时候回顾下比赛起步了
Alright thinks about time we re-watch that race start
再看看具体都发生了什么
see what really happened once again
还是有点模糊
It's all a bit of a blur still
等待比赛开始的的时候你会考虑不同可能遇到的情况
waiting before the start you you have different scenarios what's going to happen
但是我的拉力经验是，有一堆计划没什么好处
But I learned from rallycross that there's no advantage of having a lot of different plans
因为最终总不会落到你的计划当中
because there's never the plan that you plan that's going to happen in the end anyway so
我觉得最重要的是什么时候使用power boost
I think the biggest thing was when to use the hyperdrive
稍微注意观察别人是什么时候用
Trying to look at the others a little bit like when are they using theirs
然后做出调整
and trying to adjust to that
Timmy起步很不错
Timmy gets an amazing start
这时候这个距离
The distance he has here at this point
你会想：完了没戏了
You'll think, you think it's game over
实际上是Timmy在起步的大直道上就使用了power boost
Yeah but the thing here was like Timmy used his hyperdrive straight away from the start
而且他的起步位置很好，抓地力不错
and he had a very very good grid slot so he had good traction off the line
所以在这里就努力保持冷静尽量不用自己的（power boost）
So here was just all about trying to stay cool and not use mine
因为当然我很想早用
because of course I got tempted to use it early
这是我们能看到的最后一个镜头
this is the last shot we see and so
显然这里Timmy抢先
for sure at this point we think that Timmy's got it
他在前
He's in the front
但是你离得太远了
But you're so far out there
你都不在画面里
You're not even in the shot
之后吧
and then
我意识到了
And here really realized yeah
然后他就这么窜上来了
He just arrives like this this
远处一辆黑色车
Black car out in the distance
那里我滞空的时候我真的觉得我也失控了
Just when I flew there through there I actually thought that I lost it as well
好吧，我们看不到发生了啥
Right, well, we couldn't really see what happened
我们只能看到你出现在前面了
we just saw you appear in front
我们看一下你的车在视角看看发生了啥
So we've got your onboard here and we're going to take a look at what actually happened
嗯这里我主要是尽量待在外侧
So yeah here I'm just basically trying to stay wide
Timmy也是
Timmy is doing the same thing
他选择的走线是我在半决赛里走的
He took the line that I took in a semi-final
然后努力在S型减速弯走短路线
and tried to straighten out the chicane
而我是往外走了一点
But I just did an extra bit of it
嗯，我有几秒钟什么都看不见
and yeah, I was blind for a couple of
-什么都没有
Nothing
-对，我也不知道
Yeah, I don't know
所以我切到了弯心
So there I spoke to apex
这了还不错
That's okay
这里我已经
So here I'm starting to already
-就已经出弯进入直道了
Just go straight
-嗯，就把握好角度入弯
Yeah just angle it up towards the apex
你离弯心就那么几毫米的距离尽管...
Because you go like within a millimeter of the apex even though,
-嗯
Yeah
-你都没看到20米标
like you don't see that 20 meters going into it
挺完美的
Yeah it's like perfect
这基本是这一整个周末我们切到的唯一一个弯心了
It's like the the only apex we get all weekend
确实
Yeah
然后嗯进入换人区
So yeah coming towards the switch zone
首先我是要集中注意力别直接开去终点线
First of all I was trying to keep my mind straight and not going straight over the finish line
因为那里是正常你结束驾驶时要去的地方
because normally you know you go to the finish after when you're done with your driving
然后显然我要特别特别注意开启P区限速器
And then obviously I was super super cautious about keeping the pit speed
因为Q2我们遇到了这个问题
because we had an issue with that in Q2
限速器工作不是很正常
the speed limiter didn't really work
然后额我终于下车，帮你系安全带什么的
Then uh finally get out of the car and trying to sort you out with all the seat belts and stuff so
同时我也尽量让你保持冷静
I'm trying I tried to calm you down as well
所以我说放轻松
That's why I like it nice and easy
别紧张
No stress
给我打气，开始还不错
Give me a pep talk and the first one was great
赛道啊
It was ah
赛道状态不错，没有问题
It's fine it's smooth there's no problem
那是Q1的时候
That was Q1
然后你就说“放轻松放轻松”
and you're like nice and easy, nice and easy
但是外面有那么亿点点危险
But it's a bit dodgy out there
我唯一忘了的实际上是帮你擦挡风玻璃
The only thing I actually missed was that I missed to wipe the windscreen
哦谢谢
Yeah thanks
因为雨刷器不是很正常
Because the wiper didn't really work perfectly
确实
I took off yeah
我得这么开
I had to drive like this
然后我就像这样
and then I was like this was like
那玩意在中间所以你矮一点要从下面看过去，我要使劲从上面看
It was in the middle so you had that small one under and I had a little bit the other one over so I was trying to
这绝对是这整个周末最紧张的一圈了
It's the most nervous lap for sure all weekend
你要一直注意速度
When you're just trying to focus on go for pace
每个弯都要小心
and you know you're so focused on one corner after the other
那个时候
and you're in the moment
你想放慢速度注意颠簸的地方
you're trying to slow you're trying to watch for a bump
而你会看到更多的小土包，因为你开的慢了嘛
And you see more bumps because you're driving slower
然后你又想把每一弯都走好
and then you're trying to tick everything off
确保自己不犯低级错误拖累车队
make sure you don't make a silly mistake and cost the team so
我很高兴能完整跑完那一圈
it was just I was so happy to get that lap over
干得漂亮兄弟们
Nice job guys
我们的第一个冠军已经出现
Our first winners have been crowned
在沙特阿拉伯举行的具有历史意义的首届X-Prix分站赛
The historic inaugural X-Prix in Saudi Arabia
为提高人们对沙漠化的认知的一赛将永远被记住
Racing to raise awareness of desertification will be one to remember forever
但是我们的世界冒险
But our worldwide adventure
我们的电动征程
Our electric Odyssey
必须继续
must go on
海洋X-Prix分站赛是下一个
The Ocean X-Prix is next
海洋正以难以置信的速度不断变化
The oceans are now changing at a rate that's just beyond comprehension
人口
坐标
国家
地区
地形
问题
海平面上升与塑料污染
比赛日期
这真的是全球性的挑战
It is really a challenge that is global
我们每个人都有自己的任务
Each of us, we have a role to play
塞内加尔是下一站
Senegal is next stop
塞内加尔见
See you in Senegal
在塞内加尔加入我们
Join us in Senegal
我们在那里继续我们的电动征程
where we continue our Electric Odyssey
字幕：Lee-7723